<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Sheet1>
<Row>
<title>The Difference between a Congregation and the House of God</title>
<body><![CDATA[<div class="cInnerSubSection">
<p>In Haggai <i>1:7, 8,</i> Haggai urges the people to complete the building. The foundation had been laid many years earlier. But they stopped there.</p>
<p>Jesus spoke a parable about a man who laid only a foundation and then did not complete the building <i>(<a class="lbsBibleRef" href="http://biblia.com/bible/nasb95/Lk.14.28-30" data-reference="Lk.14.28-30" data-version="nasb95" data-purpose="bible-reference" target="_blank">Lk.14:28-30</a>).</i> That parable comes right in the middle of a section on being His disciple. What Jesus was implying was that evangelism without disciple-making was like laying a foundation and not completing the building. Is a foundation necessary? Yes, absolutely essential. That is the first work to be done when building a house. Is evangelism necessary? Certainly. That too is the first work to be done. But if you only evangelise and don’t make disciples, that is wasted effort – as useless as a foundation without a building.</p>
<p><i><a class="lbsBibleRef" href="http://biblia.com/bible/nasb95/Hebrews%206.1-3" data-reference="Hebrews 6.1-3" data-version="nasb95" data-purpose="bible-reference" target="_blank">Hebrews 6:1-3</a></i> warns us of such foolishness: <i>“Let us not lay again the foundation of repentance, faith, water-baptism, baptism in the Holy Spirit, and teaching about resurrection and the final judgment.”</i> All of that is just the foundation. The writer says that we must then press on to <i>perfection</i> – that is building the house. After we have converted people to Christ through evangelism, we must make those converts, disciples of Jesus who follow Him and press on to perfection.</p>
<p>So Haggai’s message is not about laying the foundation. It is about perfection – completing the building, the Body of Christ. What is the difference between a congregation and the house of God? If you cut out 50,000 stones from a quarry and bring them to the building site, that is evangelism. These stones symbolize people who are born again. But they are not a building as yet. They are just a pile of stones. That is what most evangelical congregations today are. These stones must now be built up, being placed next to each other, if they are to be an expression of Christ’s Body. That is the difficult part – to build them together into the house of God.</p>
<p>Many churches today are mere <i>congregations,</i> where one man (the pastor), like a watchman, has to ensure that no-one steals his <i>“stones”.</i> When one of his <i>“stones”</i> decides one day to join another church where he can receive more spiritual help, the watchman will complain that others are stealing <i>“his stones”!</i> But if he had built that stone into a building, it would have been impossible for anyone to steal it. If you build the Body of Christ, you won’t have to worry about others stealing your members. When stones are built together and cemented, with stones on top of them, under them, and to their left and right, who can steal them?</p>
<p>I have led a church in Bangalore since 1975; but I have never complained that anyone stole anyone from our church. Those who are being built together as a body in our midst cannot be stolen. So let us build God’s house and not just lay a foundation and accumulate stones.</p>
<p>Notice the strong rebuke the Lord gives in <i>1:9-11.</i> There is a great need in our churches for preachers who know how to speak a word of rebuke in love. There is plenty of preaching nowadays, but very little rebuke and correction. When God allows defeat or constant failure in your life, you need to stop and listen to what He is trying to tell you. Ask yourself, <i>“Why is the fruit of the Spirit missing in my life? Why is my family-life in a mess? Why is there no rain from heaven? Why is there a dryness in my life?” (1:9-11).</i> It may be because you are more concerned about earthly matters and your bank account than about your walk with the Lord!</p>
<p>When Zerubbabel and Joshua the high priest heard this prophecy, they responded to Haggai’s message immediately and said, <i>“We will start building God’s house straightaway.” or symbolically, “We will not engage in mere evangelism henceforth. We will make disciples as well. We will build Christ’s Body and not a one-man church.”</i> The church is to be like a functioning body - and not a pile of body parts, as found in anatomy laboratories - where they have many hands, legs, eyes and ears lying around, but none of them connected with each other by life. And so they cannot function <i>together.</i> Many churches today are exactly like that.</p>
<div class="cPageLinks"><a href="word_for_the_week.php"> <img src="../images/icon_index.gif" alt="View Index" title="View Index" border="0"> View Index <img src="../images/arrow.gif" border="0"></a><img src="../images/spacer.gif" width="10" height="1" border="0" alt=""><a href="../../web/mainpages/tapaalu.php?type=invite"> <img src="../images/icon_email.gif" alt="Email This Page" title="Email This Page" border="0"> E-mail this page <img src="../images/arrow.gif" border="0"></a><img src="../images/spacer.gif" width="10" height="1" border="0" alt=""><a href="print.php?type=wftw&amp;content=14_03_05"><img src="../images/icon_print.gif" alt="Print This Page" title="Print This Page" border="0"> Print this page <img src="../images/arrow.gif" border="0"></a></div></div>]]></body>
<field_wftw_author>Zac Poonen</field_wftw_author>
<field_wftw_week_number>1</field_wftw_week_number><field_wftw_description>xyz</field_wftw_description>
</Row>

<Row>
<title>River of Life and the Tree of Life</title>
<body><![CDATA[<div class="cInnerSubSection">
<p><a class="lbsBibleRef" href="http://biblia.com/bible/nasb95/Rev%2022.1-2" data-reference="Rev 22.1-2" data-version="nasb95" data-purpose="bible-reference" target="_blank">Rev 22:1-2</a>: And He showed me a river of water of life, clear as crystal, coming from the throne of God and of the Lamb. In the middle of its street and on either side of the river was the tree of life, bearing twelve kinds of fruit, yielding its fruit every month and the leaves of the tree were for the healing of the nations.</p>
<p>This is obviously a picture of the Holy Spirit.</p>
<p>In <a class="lbsBibleRef" href="http://biblia.com/bible/nasb95/Ezekiel%2047.1-12" data-reference="Ezekiel 47.1-12" data-version="nasb95" data-purpose="bible-reference" target="_blank">Ezekiel 47:1-12</a>, we read of a river, about which it says that “every living creature which swarms in every place where the river goes will live” (v.9). The river brings life wherever it goes. Jesus referred to this passage and said, “He who believes in me, as the scripture has said, out of his innermost being shall flow rivers of living water” (<a class="lbsBibleRef" href="http://biblia.com/bible/nasb95/Jn.7.37" data-reference="Jn.7.37" data-version="nasb95" data-purpose="bible-reference" target="_blank">Jn.7:37</a>, <a class="lbsBibleRef" href="http://biblia.com/bible/nasb95/Jn%207.38" data-reference="Jn 7.38" data-version="nasb95" data-purpose="bible-reference" target="_blank">38</a>).</p>
<p>Ezekiel went deeper and deeper into this river until he came to the place where his feet had to leave the earth. Thereafter, he was carried by the river. That is a picture of the Spirit-filled life - where we are no longer earth-bound. Our feet leave the earth and the Holy Spirit carries us onward and upward.</p>
<p>We see the emphasis on “clear as crystal” in relation to this river. We find a repeated emphasis on purity and transparency, again and again in chapters 21 and 22, with words such as “clear”, “transparent”, “pure as glass”, etc.</p>
<p>We notice that the river flows from the throne of God and of the Lamb, teaching us that the Holy Spirit works in power only where God and Christ are given their rightful place on the throne.</p>
<p>The opportunity that Adam lost to take part in the tree of life has now been restored to man. We find a lot of similarity between <a class="lbsBibleRef" href="http://biblia.com/bible/nasb95/Gen.%202" data-reference="Gen. 2" data-version="nasb95" data-purpose="bible-reference" target="_blank">Gen. 2</a> and <a class="lbsBibleRef" href="http://biblia.com/bible/nasb95/Rev.22" data-reference="Rev.22" data-version="nasb95" data-purpose="bible-reference" target="_blank">Rev.22</a>.</p>
<p>The tree of life symbolizes the life of God Himself - eternal life or the divine nature that we can now partake of. Eternal life does not mean “existing forever”, for those who go to the lake of fire also exist for ever. But they do not have eternal life. Eternal life means a life which had no beginning and has no end. That is the life of God Himself. That is what is symbolized in the tree of life.</p>
<p>Adam foolishly went to the tree of knowledge, instead of to the tree of life, just like many do today, who seek for Bible-knowledge rather than life. The tree of knowledge of good and evil is not found in <a class="lbsBibleRef" href="http://biblia.com/bible/nasb95/Rev.22" data-reference="Rev.22" data-version="nasb95" data-purpose="bible-reference" target="_blank">Rev.22</a>. It has disappeared.</p>
<p>In front of the tree of life, God placed a flaming sword (<a class="lbsBibleRef" href="http://biblia.com/bible/nasb95/Gen.3.24" data-reference="Gen.3.24" data-version="nasb95" data-purpose="bible-reference" target="_blank">Gen.3:24</a>). This teaches us that a sword must fall upon our Self-life, if we are to take part of the tree of life. This is why most Christians would rather go to the tree of knowledge, in front of which there is no sword. To get Bible-knowledge, we don’t have to die to our Self-life or take up the cross daily. But to partake of God’s nature, we have to “bear the dying of Jesus in our body” always (<a class="lbsBibleRef" href="http://biblia.com/bible/nasb95/2%20Cor.4.10" data-reference="2 Cor.4.10" data-version="nasb95" data-purpose="bible-reference" target="_blank">2 Cor.4:10</a>). We have to allow the sword to fall upon us.</p>
<p>The way of the cross is the way to the tree of life. The sword fell upon Jesus and He was crucified. Since we too were crucified with Him, the sword is to fall upon us too. Thus we can partake of the tree of life, which bears a new kind of fruit every month, and whose leaves bring healing.</p>
<div class="cPageLinks"><a href="word_for_the_week.php"> <img src="../images/icon_index.gif" alt="View Index" title="View Index" border="0"> View Index <img src="../images/arrow.gif" border="0"></a><img src="../images/spacer.gif" width="10" height="1" border="0" alt=""><a href="../../web/mainpages/tapaalu.php?type=invite"> <img src="../images/icon_email.gif" alt="Email This Page" title="Email This Page" border="0"> E-mail this page <img src="../images/arrow.gif" border="0"></a><img src="../images/spacer.gif" width="10" height="1" border="0" alt=""><a href="print.php?type=wftw&amp;content=14_03_04"><img src="../images/icon_print.gif" alt="Print This Page" title="Print This Page" border="0"> Print this page <img src="../images/arrow.gif" border="0"></a></div></div>]]></body>
<field_wftw_author>Zac Poonen</field_wftw_author>
<field_wftw_week_number>2</field_wftw_week_number><field_wftw_description>abc</field_wftw_description>
</Row>
</Sheet1>
